《越狱》前情提要
Previously on Prison Break:
是，我要查 第11台新闻部的电话
Yes. I'd like the number for Channel 11 News, please.
立刻挂上电话
Hang up the phone now.
我是迈克斯科菲尔德
This is Michael scofield.
我在卡特贝克汽车旅馆 11号房
I'm at the Cutback Motel, room 11.
我要自首
And I want to turn myself in.
那是哪里？
Where is that?
荷兰，我成长的地方，你知道的
It's Holland, where I grew up. You know that.
好漂亮
It's beautiful.
这留言是给犸丽的 我会在机场
This message is for Maricruz. I'll be there in the airport.
伊斯塔帕的机场等着你
In lxtapa, waiting for you.
大家好，我是莎拉，我有酒瘾
Hi. My name is sara, and I'm an addict.
你好，莎拉
Hi, sara.
我只想乖乖服刑，不想惹麻烦
I'm just looking to do my time. I don't want any trouble.
分开，你们这些犯人
Hey! Break it up, convicts.
这不好笑，好笑的是 我和卡洛琳曾经聊过你
This isn't fun, what was fun was when Caroline and I talked about you...
还有你暗恋她的事
...and the schoolboy crush that you had on her.
他还曾向她求婚
He proposed to her.
-戴伦斯 -戴伦斯
- Terrence! - Terrence!
我要离开
I'm leaving!
戴伦斯，仔细听我说
Terrence, listen to me.
听着，因为这件事、因为你 已经有太多人受苦了
Just listen, so many people have suffered because of this, because of you.
但等媒体抵达之后 你可以说出真相
But when the press get here, you can tell the truth.
你就可以结束这一切
You can end this.
-对不起 -戴伦斯，不要
- Sorry. - Terrence, no!
现在插播特别新闻快报
We interrupt this program for a special news bulletin,
蒙大拿州卡特贝克 传来新闻快报
It's breaking news out of cutback, Montana,
林克柏劳与迈克斯科菲尔德
Lincoln Burrows and Michael Scofield,,,
伊利诺州 福克斯河监狱的两名逃犯
,,, two of the prisoners who broke out of Fox River State Penitentiary in Illinois,,,
两人几次逃过警方追捕 并在逃亡过程中持续犯案
,,, have continued to elude the authorities, leaving a trail of crime in their wake,
在今天有了不同的发展
And today, they left behind something else,
我是林克柏劳，我是清白的
My name's Lincoln Burrows, and I'm innocent,
（六小时前）
-死定了 -没有其他出口
- We're done. - No other way out.
下次你想开记者会 记得找有后门的房间
Next time you hold a conference do it from a room with a back door.
让我思考一下
Just let me think.
我们是蒙大拿公路巡警
This is the Montana Highway Patrol,
迈克斯科菲尔德和林克柏劳
Michael Scofield and Lincoln Burrows,,,
请把双手举高走出来
...you need to exit with your hands in the air.
-这是警告 -你可以看到里头吗？
- This is a warning. - You got line of sight from there?
举起双手出来
Exit with your hands up.
-他怎么办？ -他毫无用处
- What about him? - Him? He's useless.
留下尸体？到处都是我们的指纹
Dead body? We got fingerprints everywhere.
你担心会被控谋杀？
You worried someone will pin a murder on you?
不然你想丢下尸体 从前门走出去？
What's your plan? Leave the body, walk out the door?
对，我们就要这么做
Yes. That's exactly what we're gonna do.
迈克斯科菲尔德和林克柏劳 把双手举高，走出来
Michael scofield and Lincoln Burrows, you need to exit with your hands up.
-调查局，不要开枪 -调查局？
- FBI, hold your fire. - FBI?
-我已制伏他们两个 -开始拍
- I have Burrows and scofield. - Start rolling.
我们要出来了，不要开枪
We're coming out. Hold your fire.
-等等，你是谁？ -联邦调查局
- Hold up, who are you? - Federal Bureau of Investigation.
-我们要去毕林斯市 -等等，给我看你的证件
- We're going to Billings. - Wait, let me see that ID again.
-过去 -把枪放下
- Okay, okay. - Drop the gun!
大家保持冷静，场面就不会难堪
Everybody calm down and this won't get ugly.
好，我要两辆警车的钥匙 马上就要
All right. I want keys to both of the cop cars, now!
-别这样 -别听他的
- Don't do it! - Don't listen to him!
-去拿钥匙，上车 -怎么回事？
- Get the keys, get in the car. - What's going on?
我们在有人受伤前离开这里
Getting out of here before anyone gets hurt.
林克，发动车子
Lincoln, start it.
-快点 -这是最后一次机会
- Come on, come on! - This is your last chance.
-我最后一次警告，放下武器 -你再靠近，我就杀了他
- I'm not gonna tell you again. - One more step, and I drop him.
快点
Come on!
帮我开门
Open my door.
（FBI分局 伊利诺州芝加哥）
欢迎归队
Welcome back.
-你觉得？ -好多了
- You feeling? - Much better.
-新消息？ -好，没问题
- Update? - Okay, you got it.
好
Yeah.
有线索了？
You got a lead on something?
福克斯河监狱的狱警 布拉德贝里克
One of the Co's from Fox River, Brad Bellick.
因为谋杀另一名狱警入狱
Got locked up last night for the murder of another guard.
等等，我们在查狱警的事？
Wait. We're looking for Co's now?
那些逃犯呢？
What about the escapees?
-斯科菲尔德和柏劳？ -目前没有新线索
- Scofield, Burrows? - Nothing on them currently.
还有富兰克林的妻子
Also, Franklin's wife...
在北达科他州被逮捕
...was taken into custody in North Dakota.
他的妻子？
His wife?
二线电话
Line two.
我是曼宏探员
This is Agent Mahone.
多久以前的事？
How long ago?
我跟你谈个条件，只要你乖乖不动 我就不轰掉你的头
I'll make you a deal. You don't move a muscle, I won't blow your head off.
-我们不会伤害你，葛瑞格 -我们要去哪？迈克
- No one's gonna hurt you, Greg. - Where are we going, Michael?
不能漫无目的 史泰门死了
We can't keep driving. Lost steadman.
-莎拉又失踪 -开大声一点
- Sara's in the wind... - Turn it up.
谋杀戴伦斯史泰门 雷诺兹总统的弟弟
,,, murder of Terrence Steadman, President Reynolds' brother,
总统目前尚未发表声明 她正在中西部进行访问
The president could not be reached as she continues to tour the Midwest,,,
在重要的几州寻求支持
,,, shoring up support in key states,
对企业家、柳橙果农 制铁工人和艺术家来说
For entrepreneurs and orange growers, iron workers and artists,,,
美国梦仍然为我们存在
,,, the American dream is alive and well for all of us,
雷诺兹今天前往科罗拉多州
Reynolds travels to colorado today,,,
预计到丹佛出席
,,, for a scheduled appearance in Denver that...
-停车 -要做什么？
- Pull over. - What for?
停车就对了
Just pull over.
出来，过来
Get out. Over here.
-你想放了那小子？ -待会吧
- You want to drop off this kid? - Later.
也该甩掉凯勒曼，我们不需要他
We should get rid of Kellerman too. We don't need him.
事实上还需要他 我们手上还有王牌
Actually, we do. We still have assets.
只是看我们如何运用
It's just a question of how we use them.
片名：越狱风云
剧名：话中有话
布拉德
Bradlee.
护士
Nurse.
-你不是护士 -你说对了
- You ain't no nurse. - You're right about that.
队长，你的伤还真好看
That's a pretty shiner you got, captain.
这一定会让你想起之前
Make you think about the times...
穿着制服进出这里的日子
...you walked around here in your fancy guard outfit.
对你看到的一切错事视而不见
Turning a blind eye to everything you saw that was wrong.
“我吗？我什么也没看到”
"Who, me? Oh, I didn't see nothing."
被视而不见感受如何？
How's that blind eye feel now?
-你这个浑蛋 -你最好习惯
- You son of a bitch. - You get used to it.
我听说独眼杰克会有大麻烦
Hear old one-eyed Jack's gonna be getting screwed in the socket.
-我死了才有可能 -不
- Over my dead body. - No.
死人感觉不到被揍
A dead man can't feel a beatdown.
而你还要尝很多顿拳脚
And you got a lot more coming your way.
好了，出去吧
Come on now. Let's go.
调查局得花一阵子才会恍然大悟
It'll take the feds a while to figure that out.
几点了？
What time is it?
-九点多 -时间会很赶
- A little after 9. - It's gonna be tight.
6小时开450里
Four hundred and fifty miles in six hours.
-你想办得到吗？ -现在就要出发
- What do you think? - Gotta move now.
眼睛看前面
Eyes front.
你瞧这个
Hey, look at this.
-好极了，准备好了吗？ -好了
- It's perfect, you ready? - Yep.
（墨西哥锡那罗亚州 15号公路）
乡间风景很美
还不错
你的口音
你是哪里人？
波多黎各
Puerto Rico.
墨西哥这一带很少有波多黎各人
你要去哪里？
伊斯塔帕
离这里很远
有上千里远
为何那么想去伊斯塔帕？ 那里有什么？
我生命中的一切
一个女人
我挚爱的女人
只希望我到的时候她还在
（威斯康辛州，阿哥马）
赖瑞，给你吃
Here, Larry, this is for you.
这可以吗？
What about this?
这是什么？太小了
What is this? This is too small.
为什么不会漂浮？为什么
Why didn't it float? Why didn't it?
我需要更多木头
I need more wood.
木头会漂浮
Wood floats.
这可以用
This'll work.
老兄
Hey, man.
你可以帮我们买啤酒吗？
We were just wondering if you could buy us some beer.
好，可以
Yeah, sure.
我可以买食物给我的狗吃吗？
Can I get some food for my dog too?
随便你，老兄
Do whatever thing you gotta do, man.
你可以留一瓶啤酒
You can keep a beer for yourself.
那可不行
Oh, no.
我爸以前是个酒鬼
My dad used to drink.
这卷带子绝对精采
You're gonna want to see this.
我们已经封闭 蒙大拿中部所有公路
We've shut down every freeway in central Montana.
-目前没有他们的踪影 -扩大范围
- So far, no sign of them. - Go wider.
派巡警到90和94号公路 一直到怀俄明州
Put troopers on 90 and 94, all the way through Wyoming.
通知白鱼镇，请他们封锁 15号公路的加拿大边境
Call Whitefish. Have them lock down the Canadian border at 15.
持续逃过警方追捕 在逃亡的过程中持续犯案
,,, have continued to elude the authorities, leaving a trail of crime in their wake,
在今天有了不同的发展
And today, they left behind something else,
我是林克柏劳，我是清白的
My name's Lincoln Burrows, and I'm innocent,
我从福克斯河州立监狱逃出
I escaped from Fox River Penitentiary,,,
因为我被冠上莫须有的罪名 而被判死刑
,,, because I was sentenced to death for a crime I did not commit,
我没有谋杀戴伦斯史泰门
I did not murder Terrence Steadman,
昨晚他在卡特贝特旅馆自杀
He committed suicide last night in the cutback Motel,,,
离他在蒙大拿州 布拉克富特的家30里远
,,,30 miles outside from his home in Blackfoot, Montana,
他因为恐惧而自杀
He killed himself out of fear,,,
他害怕那些 过去三年来软禁他的人
,,, fear of the people who've been hiding him for the past three years,
就是这些人要置我哥于死地
The same people who want my brother dead,
他们不想泄漏身份，不过听好了
They don't want you to know who they are, but know this,,,
他们贪污了数十亿美金 并谋害许多无辜人民的性命
,,, they've stolen billions of dollars and murdered dozens of innocent people,
然而他们却将我们的照片放上新闻 要你们惧怕我们
And yet, they plaster our faces on the news, and tell you to be afraid,
他们是一群跨国财团、利益团体
They are a group of multinationals, corporate interests,
他们统称为“公司”
Together, they're known as The company,
他们和政府最高层都有勾结
They are working with the highest levels of government,,,
包括美国总统在内
,,, including the President of the United States,
-做危机处理 -他们总共贪污数十亿美金
- Damage control. - They've stolen billions of dollars,
阻止消息上报纸头条
Before this hits page one.
-新闻已经播出了，长官 -去佛州森林放火
- It's already airing, sir. - Start a wildfire in Florida!
找一个塞满阿拉伯人的仓库 我不在乎
Find a storage unit full of Arabs! I do not care!
只要不是林克柏劳的新闻
As long as it's not about Lincoln Burrows!
-他们仗着免责权 -快去
- And they operate with impunity, - Go!
打着特勤局原本要保护服务人民的旗号 作为掩护
Under the cover of the Secret Service, the very people meant to protect and serve,
卡罗马堤罗站到了
Calomatillo.
祝你好运
谢谢
你也该下车了
小子，别想坐霸王车，抱歉
你不懂 我必须到伊斯塔帕，拜托你
你想惹麻烦吗？
你作菜吗？
什么？
我拔鸡毛，我妻子负责作菜
她已经去世了
抱歉，我得继续赶路
那是今天最后一班车
如果你作菜的话
我就让你今晚在我家过夜
等等
你住在这里？
对，我车子旁边的门就是我家
你知道吗？
其实我的厨艺非凡
这边请
另一个无辜的人
Much blame has been placed,,,
也遭到责难 莎拉丹奎迪医生
,,, on another innocent person, Dr, Sara Tancredi,
知道影带有多长吗？
Do we know how long the videotape lasts?
总长26分钟 网路上都看得到
Twenty-six minutes, beginning to end. It's all online.
我无法求你再给我一次机会
I know I can't ask you for another chance,
我只希望现在 你已找到安全港
I can only hope that by now you've found your safe haven,
把他们的话纪录下来，一字不漏
start a transcript. I need every word.
我害你置身于 所有医生的梦魇中
And I put you in a place that's every doctor's nightmare,
我很希望能做不同的选择
I wish I could do things differently,
通知蒙大拿分局 派探员去找摄影师
Call Montana. Send an agent to talk to the cameraman.
我要知道他看到、听到什么 他们的衣着
I wanna know what he saw, heard, what they're wearing.
-所有的细节 -好
- Anything he can give us. - Yeah.
另一人，亚历山大曼宏特别探员 谋杀了多条人命
One man, Special Agent Alexander Mahone, is responsible for multiple deaths,
他不只谋杀约翰阿布兹 和大卫阿普斯基
He murdered not only John Abruzzi and David Apolskis,,,
同时还有他上次授命追捕的逃犯
,,, but also the last fugitive he was assigned to chase,
这个人叫奥斯卡席尔斯
A man names Oscar Shales,
此人两年前从监狱脱逃
A man who escaped from prison two years ago,,,
目前仍然是本国的通缉要犯之一
,,, who remains one of this country's most wanted,,,
-但他已永远不可能被找到 -这家伙疯了
- ,,, despite the fact he will never be found, - Guy's nuts.
他们会尽可能 将谋杀过程合法化
They'll do whatever it takes to make the deaths look official,
用职务所需的理由搪塞 失踪人口
Like they happened in the line of duty, Disappearances,,,,
-谢谢 -不客气，拿去吧
- Hey, thank you. - Sure. Here you go.
那些木头要做什么？
What's the wood for?
我要建一艘木筏
I'm building a raft.
如果要去荷兰，我需要更多木头
I need more wood if I'm gonna make it to Holland.
-荷兰？ -对
- Holland? - Yeah.
你想看我的木筏吗？
You want to see it? The raft?
你要搭这艘木筏 从这里到荷兰？
You're gonna try to get from here to Holland in that?
祝你好运，梦幻岛先生
Yeah, good luck, Gilligan.
我去上厕所
I'm gonna take a leak.
你怎么知道要往哪个方向走？
How are you gonna know where you're going?
你有地图之类的东西吗？
Do you have like a map or anything?
有，我有
Yeah, I do.
就在
It's right...
就在这里
oh, it's right here.
那是你的地图？
That's your map?
我诚心希望你达成目标
Well, I really hope you make it.
每天早上我醒来都想着
You know, every morning I wake up and wonder...
不知消失在世上是什么感觉
...what it would be like to just disappear.
你却真的打算消失
And you're just gonna do it.
我觉得很棒
I think it's great.
好
Okay.
你的手怎么了？
What happened to your arm?
我爸也有酒瘾
My dad drinks too.
怎么回事？
What's going on?
-没事 -不别
- Oh, nothing. - No, no. No, no, don't...
-我 -放开我
- I... - Let me go.
-我只是想帮你 -放手，住手
- I just want to fix it. I just want to make... - Let me go. Stop.
麦特，带我回家好吗？
Matt, will you take me home, please?
不，我只是
No, I...
怪胎
Freak.
布拉德，感觉如何？
All right, now, Brad. How we doing?
不是很好
I could be better.
对，那个挫伤的确严重 但24小时后应该会消肿
Yeah, that's a nasty contusion, but it should go down in about 24 hours.
这里有 把你转回大牢房的文件
I got your paperwork here for your transfer back to gen pop.
这么快？
Already?
进来就得出去，规定就是这样
Move them in, move them out. You know the policy.
凯蒂
Katie.
你今天看起来很美
You look nice today.
你在这工作十多年了吧？
You've worked here over 10 years, right?
差不多
Something like that.
我们当朋友也很久了
That's a long time we've been friends.
布拉德，如果你认为我能 让你不用回大牢房，我办不到
Brad, if you think I can pull some strings to keep you out of gen pop, I can't do that.
求求你，不要把我送回去
Please, please, you can't send me back there.
你明知他们会揍我 还要见死不救吗？
Do you want that responsibility, knowing what they'll do to me?
拜托，听我说 再一晚就好
Just listen, please. One more night.
让我今晚待在这里
Just let me stay here tonight.
我知道你有办法
I know you can do that.
还有你回家时 帮帮忙不要锁门
And when you go home, just leave that door open for me.
他们在背后墙上挂上床单
They hung a sheet behind their heads on the wall.
是其中一个，带枪的人
One of them, the guy with the gun...
柏劳和斯科菲尔德说要赶路时 在旁边找到的
...he found it while Burrows and scofield were talking about how far they had to go.
斯科菲尔德说 6小时要开450里的车
Scofield said something about 450 miles in six hours.
-450里到哪里？ -我不知道
- Four hundred fifty miles to where? - I don't know.
6小时赶450里的路
Four hundred fifty miles in six hours.
圆圈上任何一点 都可能是他们的目的地
Any point on this circle could be their final destination.
时速75里，停下加油
Seventy-five miles per hour, stopping for gas.
-的确可行 -是
- It's doable. - Yeah.
他们在哪里？
Where are they?
我不确定，我还需要时间
I'm not sure. I still need more time.
曼宏先生，你该尽快处理 他们已造成无法挽回的伤害
This can't happen fast enough. They've already done irreparable damage.
斯科菲尔德在一间仓库拍下影带
Scofield made the video in a storage facility...
地点在大瀑布市和海伦那之间 时间在日出后不久
...somewhere between Great Falls and Helena not long after sunrise.
目击者表示，他们从那里
From there, the witness said...
要去的地点有450里远
...that they had 450 miles to get to where they were going.
有西雅图、波特兰、芉湖城，丹佛
There's seattle, Portland, salt Lake, Denver...
-丹佛？ -对，怎么了？
- Denver? - Yes, what?
总统下午会在该地演讲
The president is speaking there this afternoon.
-下午三点 -是他们拍影带六小时后
- Three o'clock. - Six hours from when they made the video.
他们要去找总统
They're going after the president.
（丹佛）
林克柏劳和迈克斯科菲尔德 两名逃犯所拍摄的影带
A tape made by escaped convicts Lincoln Burrows and Michael Scofield,,,
立刻被司法部称为毫无根据
,,, was immediately dismissed by the Justice Department as entirely baseless,,,
现在回到今天的新闻焦点
,,, which brings us back to the story we'll be continuing to follow throughout the day,
恐怖威胁指数已提升到橙色
Terror threat has been raised to orange,,,
几位阿拉伯裔美国人 承租的仓库忽然遭到查封
,,, as a storage unit rented by several Arab-Americans was suddenly seized,
消息被封杀了 消息被湮灭无法上头条
They buried it. Dumped it off the front page and buried it.
这是他们的工作
It's what they do.
他们要怎么玩不重要 消息已经放出去了
They can spin it all they want. It's out there now.
假以时日 影带会有效果的
Give it time, the tape is gonna work.
-不能找到她，这也没用 -找到她还算简单
- This is a Hail Mary if we don't get to her. - Getting to her is easy.
-之后该怎么做才是难题 -所以要尽速找到她
- What we do after's the problem. - Which is why it has to happen quickly.
一旦被人发现我们找到她 就没戏唱了
Once anyone knows we have her, the curtain comes down.
-我去通知白宫取消 -不要
- I'll notify the White House to cancel... - No.
行程有一点变更 两兄弟会察觉，又藏匿起来
If there's a change, the brothers will know something's up and go back into hiding.
我们以前逮过他们 再抓到不是不可能
We've found them before. We can find them again.
他们不是宠物，卫勒探员
These are not pets, Agent Wheeler.
谢谢，这点我很清楚
Yeah, thanks. I'm pretty clear on that.
可是如果你要用总统当诱饵 绝对不可能
But if you use the commander in chief as bait, that's not gonna...
你对我办案的方式有意见吗？
You have a problem with the way that I do things?
对
Yeah.
而且不只我一人
And I'm not the only one.
真的吗？
Is that right?
风纪部已经请我从现在起 呈报你一切的行动
Internal Affairs has asked me to run all your moves through them from here on out.
那么拿起你的笔
Then, get a pen...
一字不露的呈报回去
...and make sure you get this word for word.
总统的行程不会改变
The president's day does not change.
我们唯一的线索 就是知道他们的目的地
The only lead we have is that we know where these men are headed.
所以这件事不能泄漏出去
So we're gonna keep quiet about this...
等他们上钩
...and let them come.
现在滚出我的办公室
Now get out of my office.
全美已经有无数人认识他们俩
They're two of the most recognizable faces in America.
他们怎么会有办法 可以接近总统？
How do they think they're gonna get anywhere near the president?
因为现在不光只有他们两人
Because it's not just the two of them anymore.
我要去仔细研究这段影带
I'm gonna go take a closer look at that video.
长官，恕我直言，关于总统
If I may, sir, the president...
你确定不要通知她这件事吗？
...are you certain we should keep her in the dark on this?
因为其实
Because there is...
有个场合 她可以派上用场
...a scenario where she could be useful.
有危险的人的确是她，长官
It is her ass on the line, sir.
我想大家心知肚明
I think we're pretty clear...
以前危险逼近时 她都会自己采取行动
...she's been known to get her hands dirty when that line gets too close.
也许我们该让她知道
Maybe we should let her know...
这次的危险有多近
...just how close it is.
身上没钱要旅行很困难
Travelling without money is difficult.
鸡肉好吃吗？
我妻子的比较好吃
她去世多久了？
一个礼拜
我很遗憾
你们结婚多久了？
42年
有什么秘砕吗？
你结婚了？
希望很快能结婚
结婚需要钱，你知道吧
谢谢你提醒我
你在逃离某些东西吗？
我在追求某种东西
你靠着希望苟活
你的口气似乎觉得这不是好事
脱离正道的人才会靠希望苟活
后面房间有一张床
谢谢
不，是我该谢谢你
孤独用餐是最凄惨的事 晚安
他们伪装空间的工作做得很彻底 没有倒影或反光
They did a good job masking the room. No reflections or flares.
声音特征，有教堂钟声 施工、车辆噪音之类的吗？
Audio markers: Church bells, construction, traffic. Anything?
空间音调显示他们在大空间里 约有10万立方尺
The room tone tells us they were in a large space, about 100,000 cubic feet.
所以摄影师的说法相符
So the kid with the camera, his story matches up.
我们确认了光线的时间
We clocked the quality of light with the time of day.
时间和地点都符合
It fits his wheres and whens.
好，说话内容
All right, content.
寻常的线索 眼睛、手、脚
The usual tells: Eyes, hands, feet.
柏劳有出庭划面 可以相互比对
Burrows, we're able to baseline off his trial footage...
所以他的部份更为清楚
...so we got even more clarity there.
我从福克斯河监狱逃出
I escaped from Fox River Penitentiary,,,
因为我被冠上莫须有的罪名而被判死刑
,,, because I was sentenced to death for a crime I did not commit,
-我没有谋杀戴伦斯史泰门 -这里
- I did not murder Terrence Steadman, - okay, there.
他的眼睛，有看到吗？
The eyes. See it?
眼睛往左飘，再往上
A slight shift to the left, then up.
对，这里的眨眼率 比习惯增加了
Yeah, the blink rate's up here verses the pattern.
他昨晚在卡特贝特旅馆自杀
He committed suicide last night in the cutback Motel,,,
离他在蒙大拿 布拉克富特的家30里处
,,,30 miles outside from his home in Blackfoot, Montana,
-他在说谎 -似乎是如此
- He's lying. - Seems so.
这里，柏劳双手交叉
Okay, here. Burrows, arms folded.
他在保护自己
He's protecting himself.
说这些话时他没有信心
Not a lot of confidence in these words.
用职务所需的理由搪塞
Like they happened in the line of duty,
他的话中有话
They mean something other than what he's saying.
他的姿势，缩肩膀的动作 有强调的意味
The posture. Shoulders in for emphasis.
他要你注意这部份
He wants your attention here.
这里
Okay, there.
-喉结 -放大划面
- Adam's apple. - Zoom in, zoom in.
看，他在吞口水
See? He's swallowing.
喉咙干燥，他说谎
Throat's dry. That's a lie.
-对 -他的动作非常典型
- Yeah. - His behavior is textbook.
如果影带能透露出 他们到丹佛的计划
If there's anything about what they plan on doing in Denver...
从他们身上一定查得出来
...they're gonna tell us.
-用那种方式说太真诚了 -当然真诚，这是实话
- Lf you say it that way, it plays too earnest. - Of course it will, it's the truth.
对，但说实话只会让他们办事轻松
But the truth sends them home to their wife and kids.
说谎他们才会继续追查
Lies will keep them busy.
我不要向全国说谎
I'm not telling a lie to the whole country.
-这是我们唯一的表达机会 -你要说什么我不在乎
- It's our one chance to say it how... - say whatever the hell you want.
说你是绿灯侠我也没差 我了解他们分析影像的手法
Tell them you're the Green Lantern. I know how they break down these tapes.
我有做过 每个小细节都是重点
I've done it. Every detail matters.
宝拉登的右腿跨在左腿上 和相反方向的涵义完全不同
Bin Laden crosses his legs right over left tells something different than left over right.
我们传达的目的不同
It's not the same message.
对他们都一样
To them, it is.
如果要让计划成功 你嘴里说的话
If you want this plan to work, whatever you say with your mouths...
要和你的眼睛和身体 传达出不同的涵义
...you need to say something different with your bodies and eyes.
眼睛往左上飘
Slightly up and to the left.
对
Yes.
另一个无辜的人也遭到责难
Much blame has been placed on another innocent person,,,
总统车队进入市区 目前没见到两兄弟
President's motorcade is rolling in. No sign of the brothers.
这里 斯科菲尔德的手在做什么？
Right there. What's scofield doing with his hand?
我们已经给他们许多混淆的讯息 再添加一点如何？
We've been throwing them fastballs. What do you say we mix it up a little?
例如什么？
Like what?
我觉得是摩斯密码
I think it's Morse code.
-内容是什么？ -现在他说了一句话
- For what? - Well, right now, we got a phrase:
“水是温的”
"The water is warm."
知道是什么意思吗？
Any idea what that might mean?
-这有什么意义？ -没意义
- What the hell does that mean? - Nothing.
调查局要好一阵子 才会恍然大悟
It'll take the feds a while to figure out.
我们会派人去周遭的郡 调查水温
We have teams checking the surrounding counties for water temps.
对，可能是给共犯的讯息
Yeah, it might be a message to an accomplice.
该市有北波拉河贯穿，也许
The North Platte River runs through the city. Maybe...
这话毫无意义 他们身边有个前特勤局探员
It doesn't mean anything. He's with an ex-secret service guy.
他们是刻意要我们 去查那些线索
They're spoon-feeding us every lead they want us to follow.
所以这是调虎离山 让他们去找总统
So this is a distraction while they go after the president.
他们一定早料到 我们会不信任影带
They had to know the tape would be discredited.
早料到我们会约谈摄影师
They had to know that we'd talk to the cameraman.
-背后一定事有蹊跷 -另一个无辜的人
- There's something else going on. - Much blame has been placed,,,
也遭到责难 莎拉丹奎迪医生
,,, on another innocent person, Dr, Sara Tancredi,
（密苏里州，堪萨斯市 珠尔葛罗图书馆）
莎拉，如果你在听的话
Sara, if you're listening,,,
我无法求你再给我一次机会
,,, I know I can't ask you for another chance,
我只希望现在 你已找到安全港
I only hope by now you've found your safe haven,
我利用了你 利用了你救世的天职
I took advantage of you, of your commitment to help others,,,
害你置身于所有医生的梦魇
,,, and put you in a place that's every doctor's nightmare,
莎拉，如果你在听的话
Sara, if you're listening,,,
我无法求你再给我一次机会
,,, I know I can't ask you for another chance,
我只希望现在 你已找到安全港
I only hope by now you've found your safe haven,
我利用了你 利用了你救世的天职
I took advantage of you, of your commitment to help others,,,
害你置身于所有医生的梦魇
,,, and put you in a place that's every doctor's nightmare,
利用了你救世的天职
,,, of your commitment to help others,,,
害你置身于所有医生的梦魇
,,, and put you in a place that's every doctor's nightmare,
我想过许多道歉的方式 但我只能用一种
I've considered many ways to apologize, but I must arrive at one,
这里也是一样
It's more of the same here.
他的肢体语言有异 我看他的举止不是真心的
Body language, his tells. If you ask me, it doesn't look like he means this at all.
-我不在乎他的举止，再放 -我看不出
- Don't care what it looks like. Play it. - I don't see how...
再放一次
Play it again.
我只希望现在 你已找到安全港
I only hope by now you've found your safe haven,
我利用了你 利用了你救世的天职
I took advantage of you, of your commitment to help others,,,
害你置身于所有医生的梦魇
,,, and put you in a place that's every doctor's nightmare,,,,
他的声音，你不觉得他对她
His voice. Would you say he sounds sincere...
说话的声音 是否比谈罪名的时候诚恳？
...when talking to her as opposed to talking about their crimes?
是可以这么说
I guess you could say that.
我是这么认为，你觉得呢？
I did say that. Would you say that?
我很希望能做不同的选择 但已经太迟了
I wish I could do this differently, but it's too late for that now,
-对 -对你和其他人都太迟了
- Yeah. - It's too late for you and for others,
人们被谋杀
People murdered,,,,
这无关戴伦斯史泰门 也无关他们的清白
This isn't about Terrence steadman and it's not about their innocence.
-什么？ -他们不想找总统
- What? - They're not after the president.
他们在找那个医生 把莎拉丹奎迪的一切资料都给我
They're going after the doctor. I want everything we got on sara Tancredi.
亲友、笔友
Friends, families, pen pals.
就算是写感谢卡给她的人 都要查出下落
If anybody wrote her a thank-you note, I wanna know where the hell they are.
立刻办
Now!
你们在哪里找到他的？
镇外，他在15号公路往南走
我们认出你的车，但不认识他
我懂了
很高兴你们带他回来
我忘了给他加油的钱
所以你真的把车借给他
真抱歉
需要警察把你的车开回来吗？
没关系，离这里不远
他自己可以走
找到你的女孩
再找回你的正道
莎拉丹奎迪，父母双亡
Sara Tancredi. Dad dead, mom dead.
电子邮件信箱联络人非常少 也很少使用
E-mail account shows a minimal list of contacts, with very little activity.
信用卡多半用来买杂货 偶而会买衣服
Credit cards used mostly for groceries, sporadic clothing shopping...
以及单人电影票
...and the purchase of single movie tickets.
还有妇产科记录显示
And ob-gyn records tell us...
近来她几乎没有性生活
...she's had very little in the way of sexual relationships recently.
老实说 我想她生活中只有工作
Tell you the truth, I would say the bulk of her life was her work.
长官，你要去哪里？
Excuse me, sir. Where are you going?
（清洁工陈尸于 蒙大拿汽车旅馆）
（逃犯留下尸体）
看来我们只除掉了清洁工
Apparently, we took out a janitor.
等搞垮他们，一切都会水落石出
When it all comes down, all of this will get cleared up.
没有莎拉，就不可能搞垮他们
Well, it ain't coming down if we don't get sara.
她会来的
She'll be here.
我要和我弟弟谈谈
I wanna speak to my brother.
我们得开始想她不来时的对策
We gotta start thinking about what to do if she doesn't show.
或是她来之后的对策
Or if she does.
万一这家伙帮助我们
What if the only reason this guy's helping us...
只为了取得莎拉手上的资讯 怎么办？
...is to get whatever information sara has?
如果这只是个大陷阱怎么办？
What if this is just one giant setup?
晚安
Well, good night.
你也该回家了
About time you come home.
你又跟姓非塔克的 小子出去？
You out with that Feytek boy again?
-莎夏 -走开
- Sasha. - No!
你也许长得像我
You may look like me...
但找男人方面是遗传你妈 你说是吧？
...but you take after your mom when it comes to the boys, now, don't you?
希望我的品味比她好一点
Hopefully, with a little better taste.
该死，你最好对我尊敬一点
Damn it, girl, you are gonna show me some respect.
-我知道莎拉的朋友不多 -她喜欢独来独往
- I know sara didn't have many friends. - She's sort of a Ioner.
你是她的朋友
But you were her friend.
我希望是的
I like to think so, yes.
但你不知道她现在的下落？
But you have no idea where she is now?
不知道
No.
这是那两兄弟的影带对话内容
This is a transcript of the scofield-Burrows videotape.
我把他对莎拉说的话标示出来
I highlighted the part where he talks directly to sara.
你有看出什么吗？
Mean anything to you?
没有
No.
你不知道她和他会面的地点 如果他有这打算的话？
You have no idea where she might meet him, if that's his plan?
不知道
No.
布拉德贝里克还在医务室吗？
Is Brad Bellick still here in the infirmary?
对，怎么了？
Yeah. Why?
你现在一定在窃笑
You must be loving this.
我不是大老远来幸灾乐祸的
I didn't drive all this way to gloat.
那你到底是来做什么？
Well, then, what the hell you come here for?
首先，我得向你致敬
First, I really gotta tip my cap to you.
你追查逃犯的能力 比我的属下厉害多了
You've managed to draw a bead on the convicts than my own staff.
感谢你的赞许
Well, thanks for the "attaboy."
但如你所见 惩治体系并不以为然
But as you can see, the correctional system doesn't share your gratitude.
我不会占用你太多时间 但是我有几个疑问
I won't take much of your time. I have a few questions.
-什么事？ -莎拉丹奎迪
- About? - Sara Tancredi.
她来这里应征的履历上 把你列为推荐人
She listed you as a reference on her job application to work here.
你跟她很熟吗？
You know her well?
如果你能把我调到单人牢房 我就会跟她很熟
I'd know her a lot better if you can get my ass moved to ad seg.
我无法影响惩治局，你很清楚的
I have no influence with the DoC. You know that.
想请我帮忙，你就得想办法
You want my help, you do.
我可以找典狱长想想办法
I'll talk to the warden, see what I can do.
不过你要先给我答案
Right after you give me some answers.
斯科菲尔德喜欢用暗号 传讯息给莎拉
Scofield likes to communicate with sara via coded message.
你有任何部份感到熟悉吗？
You recognize anything here?
是否看得出 他想告诉她什么？
Anything that he may be trying to tell her?
看不出来，他只是在道歉
No. I mean, he's saying he's sorry.
但道歉对高傲医生 又有什么用？
Not that that's gonna do any good with Dr. Cold shoulder.
不过
But...
怎么了？
What?
单人牢房
Ad seg.
好
Yeah.
你看这里
You see here?
他提到“再一次机会” 和“安全港”
Where it says this stuff about "another chance" and "safe haven"?
-应该是出自那一本“圣经” -什么圣经？
- That's out of the Big Book. - What big book?
戒酒无名会 莎拉还在戒毒当中
Alcoholics Anonymous. Sara's in recovery.
对，这我知道
Yeah, I'm aware of that.
这些是戒酒无名会使用的
Those are the names of some of the chapters...
书籍里的章节名称
...in the book they use in AA.
你手上有戒酒匿名会的书吗？
Do you have a copy of the Alcoholics Anonymous book?
莎拉，如果你在听的话
Sara, if you're listening,,,
我无法求你 再给我一次机会
,,, I know I can't ask you for another chance,
（再一次机会）
我只希望现在 你已找到安全港
I can only hope by now you've found your safe haven,
（安全港）
我利用了你 利用你救世的天职
I took advantage of you, of your commitment to help others,
我害你置身于 所有医生的梦魇
I put you in a place that's every doctor's nightmare,
（鲍伯医生的梦魇）
（俄亥俄州亚克朗的 圣汤犸斯医院）
我想过许多道歉的方式 但我只能用一种
I've considered many ways to apologize, but I must arrive at one,
（圣汤犸斯医院）
- It's getting late. - I know.
-不早了 -我知道
She's not here.
她不在这里
我也知道
I know that too.
她可能没看懂我的讯息
There is a chance she didn't get the message.
或是她受够这一切了
Or maybe she's just sick of all this.
这女孩在希拉甩了你
I mean, the girl bailed on you back in Gila.
你为何还认为这次她会赶来？
What makes you think she's gonna come running back now?
就是过去三个月 让我们继续走下去的东西
The same thing that's been keeping us going for the last three months.
-信念 -好吧
- Faith. - Yeah, well...
信念敌不过现实，老弟
Reality's kicking faith's ass, man.
-迈克鹤 -听着
- Michael crane,,,, - Look...
-等等 -等？
- Wait, wait. - Wait?
-我们不能再等下去了 -你听
- Man, we can't wait anymore. - Listen, listen.
再广播一次，迈克鹤
Once again, Michael crane,,,
请到服务台
,,, please report to the front desk,
有您的电话
You have a telephone call,
对，莎拉丹奎迪
Yeah, sara Tancredi.
对，她可能和他在一起
Right, she might be with him. Just...
没错，通知亚克朗警察 派出所有警力
Yes. Just call the local police in Akron and tell them to get everyone they have...
立刻赶到圣汤犸斯医院
...over to st. Thomas Hospital now.
我是迈克鹤 我听到有我的电话
Michael Crane. I think you've got a phone call for me.
拿去吧
Here you go.
谢谢
Thank you.
我是鹤先生
This is Mr. Crane.
这名字比纸鹤先生好听
It sounded better than origami.
即使你猜出讯息 我也不确定你会回应
Even if you got the message, I wasn't sure you'd respond.
我来不及赶过去 只能想到这种办法
I couldn't get to you in time. This is the only thing I could think of.
我发过誓不再烦你
I swore I'd leave you alone...
可是我非得联络你不可
...but I had to contact you.
因为我手上有资讯？
Because I have something?
你怎么知道？
How'd you know?
迈克，我在希拉原本要回去找你
Michael, back in Gila, I was coming back to you,
但有人把我抓走
somebody grabbed me...
他们说我父亲 把某样东西交给我
...and they told me that my father had given me something.
他们有伤害你吗？
Did someone hurt you?
我逃走了
I got away,
迈克，我不想再这样继续下去了
Michael, I want for this to be over.
我也是
That makes two of us.
你认为有可能吗？
Do you think that's possible?
有你的帮忙就有可能
With your help, yes.
现在都要靠 你父亲给你的东西
It's just a question of looking at whatever it is your father gave you.
那只是
It's just...
只是一把钥匙
It's just a key.
我们可以查清楚
Well, we'll figure it out.
一起查
Together.
这句话很动听
I like the sound of that.
我也觉得
Me too.
你好，保罗
Hello, Paul,
总统女士，好久不见
Madame President, it's been a while.
我知道，我是打来道歉的
I know, I'm calling to apologize,
好
okay.
我非常抱歉 情况实在太复杂
I'm so sorry, It all just got away from me,
最后我却伤害到 唯一永远支持我的人
And I ended up hurting the one person who's always been at my side,
我要你回家，保罗
I want you to come home, Paul,
我们一起把事情解决
We can fix this together,
但不能让这两兄弟
But not with those brothers,,,
流窜全国 破坏你帮我建立的地位
,,, running around the country, tearing down the very office you helped me build,
卡洛琳
Caroline.
我希望弥补你
I want to make it up to you,
请你逮捕他们，保罗
Please bring them in, Paul,,,
之后一切就能恢复原状
,,, and everything can go back to the way it was,
我得走了，我们回头见
I have to go now, I'll see you soon,
你跟莎拉通上话了？
Did you talk to sara?
几天之后，无论如何 一切都会结束
In a few days, this should all be over, one way or the other.
我绝对同意
Absolutely.